<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Biometric Systems</title><link>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/</link><description>Recent content on Biometric Systems</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Course</title><link>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/course/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/course/</guid><description>Course # Contact # Piotr Giedziun
piotr.giedziun@pwr.edu.pl
Reporting requirements # Technical report provide a record of your work and decision making. It should aggregate data and present the data. Use this guide to find out more.</description></item><item><title>Lab 1 - Intro</title><link>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/labs/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/labs/intro/</guid><description>Introduction # Introduction to Machine Learning and Python - required to complete the course.
Pre-read (Required) # https://www.kaggle.com/learn/python (Lessons 1-6) https://www.kaggle.com/learn/intro-to-deep-learning (Lessons 1-3) https://www.kaggle.com/learn/computer-vision (Lessons 1-4) Literature (Optional) # Christopher M. Bishop. (2007). Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning Sebastian Raschka (2019). Python Machine Learning: Machine Learning and Deep Learning with Python John M. Zelle, Guido van Rossum. (2016). Python Programming: An Introduction to Computer Science Demo project # This is a handwritten digit recognizer created during the class.</description></item><item><title>Lab 2 - Face</title><link>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/labs/face/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/labs/face/</guid><description>Face biometrics # The class covers face detection, face recognition and methods of spoofing them with deep fakes.
Pre-read (Required) # https://www.tensorflow.org/guide/keras/sequential_model https://scikit-image.org/docs/dev/auto_examples/features_detection/plot_hog.html https://opencv24-python-tutorials.readthedocs.io/en/latest/py_tutorials/py_objdetect/py_face_detection/py_face_detection.html Demo project # Class content # Introduction to face detection algorithms (Histogram of Oriented Gradients, Haar Cascades, Deep Neural Network). The aim of the task is to get to know the methods and their strengths and weaknesses.</description></item><item><title>Lab 3 - Iris</title><link>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/labs/iris/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/labs/iris/</guid><description>Iris recognition # Identifying the characteristics of the iris is a similar process to identifying it with the facial pattern and fingerprint. The system segments the image of the iris and then converts it into a pattern which is compared with the pattern. Iris readers often use an additional system to illuminate the eye with near-infrared light.
Pre-read (Required) # https://www.tensorflow.org/addons/tutorials/losses_triplet https://www.tensorflow.org/tensorboard/tensorboard_projector_plugin https://www.</description></item><item><title>Lab 4 - Voice</title><link>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/labs/voice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/labs/voice/</guid><description>Voice biometrics # Identification and voice recognition are issues that have a number of practical applications in automation, authentication and security. It is a popular method of remote authorization thanks to its non-invasive and accessibility (e.g. telephone, personal computer). This method combines physical and behavioral elements. It uses a person&amp;rsquo;s acoustic features, which are shaped by biological features (e.g. the shape of the larynx) and by additional behavioral features such as stress, rhythm, intonation and vocabulary selection.</description></item><item><title>Lab 5 - Keystroke</title><link>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/labs/keystroke/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/labs/keystroke/</guid><description>Keystroke dynamics # Identifying or confirming the identity of an individual based on the manner and the rhythm of typing on a keyboard. During the labolatory you will learn different approaches for Keystroke Dynamics (such as anomaly detection, clusterization, etc.).
Pre-read (Required) # Wojciech Wodo, Marek Klonowski, Piotr Syga, &amp;ldquo;SOME REMARKS ON KEYSTROKE DYNAMICS: Global Survillience, Retriving Information and Simple Countermeasures&amp;rdquo;, Proceedings of 7th International Conference on Security and Cryptography SECRYPT 2012, Rome 2012, ISBN: 978-989-8565-24-2 Wojciech Wodo, Lucjan Hanzlik, &amp;ldquo;Identity Security in Biometric Systems Based on Keystroking&amp;rdquo;, Proceedings of the 8th International Conference on Security and Cryptography: SECRYPT 2013, Reykjavik 2013, ISBN: 978-989-8565-73-0 Guansong Pang, Chunhua Shen, Longbing Cao, Anton van den Hengel, Deep Learning for Anomaly Detection: A Review</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://piotrgiedziun.github.io/biometric-systems/docs/resources/</guid><description>Resources # Course website - Wojciech Wodo, PhD Getting started with Python Intro to Machine Learning</description></item></channel></rss>